Finding Aid for the Norman Cousins Papers LSC.1385
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Volume 5
  - Books
    - Words of Albert Schweitzer
      - [Words of Albert Schweitzer material] (Box 1808, Box 1809)
  - Broadcasts
    - [broadcasts arranged chronologically], 1949-1961 (Box 1701, Box 1702, Box 1703)
  - Conferences
    - Dartmouth Conference 1
      - Report to President (Box 1348, Folder 1)
      - NC speech to Soviet Peace Committee (Box 1348, Folder 2)
      - Dartmouth Conference [corresp.] (Box 1348, Folder 3)
      - Draft for joint statement (Box 1348, Folder 4)
      - Bios on Dartmouth Conf. participants (Box 1348, Folder 5)
      - Dartmouth Conference - agenda (Box 1348, Folder 6)
      - Participants - first conference (Box 1348, Folder 7)
      - Press release (Box 1348, Folder 8)
      - Itinerary (Box 1348, Folder 9)
      - Financial (US-USSR Conf.) (Box 1348, Folder 10)
      - Reynolds, Lloyd G. - Observations on _____ development, travel diary (Box 1348, Folder 11)
      - Interpretation (Box 1348, Folder 12)
      - Corresp. re facilities (Box 1348, Folder 13)
      - Travel arrangements (Box 1348, Folder 14)
      - [Editorial report from world press] (Box 1348, Folder 15)
      - Rapporteur's notes - more in binders (Box 1348, Folder 16)
      - Press clips (Box 1348, Folder 17)
      - Agenda (Box 1348, Folder 18)
      - Corresp. with Soviet Peace Committee (Box 1348, Folder 19)
      - Wheat (Box 1349, Folder 1)
      - Background material (Box 1349, Folder 2)
      - Psychological (Box 1349, Folder 3)
      - Arms control (Box 1349, Folder 4)
      - Structured peace (Box 1349, Folder 5)
      - Names & addresses of Russian participants (Box 1349, Folder 6)
      - Citizen's role (Box 1349, Folder 7)
      - First meeting - document 11 (Box 1349, Folder 8)
      - Second & third mtg. - document 12 (Box 1349, Folder 9)
      - Document 13 (Box 1349, Folder 10)
      - Document 14 (Box 1349, Folder 11)
      - Eighth & ninth meetings - document 16 (Box 1349, Folder 12)
      - Sixth & seventh meetings - document 17 (Box 1349, Folder 13)
      - Russian translation of rapporteur's notes (Box 1349, Folder 14)
      - Economic (Box 1349, Folder 15)
      - Bios on Dartmouth Conf. participants (Box 1349, Folder 16)
      - Soviet Peace Committees Conf. (Box 1349, Folder 17)
      - Dartmouth Conf. press releases (Box 1349, Folder 18)
      - Rapporteur's final report (Box 1350, Folder 1)
      - Dartmouth Conference - staff notices (Box 1350, Folder 2)
      - Principal Soviet accounts - first meeting (Box 1350, Folder 3)
      - Millis (Box 1350, Folder 4)
      - [binder with conf. activities] (Box 1350, Folder 5)
      - [binder with conf. activities] (Box 1350, Folder 6)
    - Dartmouth Conference 2
      - Agenda (Box 1351, Folder 1)
      - [correspondence] (Box 1351, Folder 2)
      - To be filed (Box 1351, Folder 3)
      - Reference materials for NC for USSR (Box 1351, Folder 4)
      - Staff (Box 1351, Folder 5)
      - Participants - 2nd Dartmouth Conf. 1961 Crimea (Box 1351, Folder 6)
      - Agenda (Box 1351, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence (Box 1351, Folder 8)
      - Corresp. with State (Box 1351, Folder 9)
      - "A Russian Breakfast" (Box 1351, Folder 10)
        includes photos
      - Handwritten notes (Box 1351, Folder 11)
      - Notes (typed) on and from sessions (Box 1351, Folder 12)
      - Sen. Wm. Benton's notes on Conf. (Box 1351, Folder 13)
      - "Russian Diary" (Box 1351, Folder 14)
      - A Soviet press release (Box 1351, Folder 15)
      - Press clips (Box 1351, Folder 16)
      - Crimea (Box 1351, Folder 17)
      - To be filed [includes corresp., agenda, etc.] (Box 1351, Folder 18-20)
      - Publicity (Box 1352, Folder 1)
      - Bios (Box 1352, Folder 2)
      - Dartmouth Conference in Crimea May 1961 (Box 1352, Folder 3)
      - Press release (Box 1352, Folder 4)
      - MH do in Russia - Dartmouth II (Box 1352, Folder 5)
      - State Dept. (Box 1352, Folder 6)
      - Financial (Box 1352, Folder 7)
      - Hints on Russia (Box 1352, Folder 8)
      - Travel Arrangements (Box 1352, Folder 9)
      - May 10 dinner (Box 1352, Folder 10)
      - Inquiry letters (Box 1352, Folder 11)
      - Corresp. with Russians (Box 1352, Folder 12)
      - Arrangements (Box 1352, Folder 13)
      - Corresp. with Soviets (Box 1352, Folder 14)
      - Crimea notes (Box 1352, Folder 15)
    - Dartmouth Conference 3
      - Participants Andover Conf. 1962 (Box 1353, Folder 1)
      - Master schedule (Box 1353, Folder 2)
      - Oct. 19 dinner (Box 1353, Folder 3)
      - Press release - 3rd Dartmouth Conf. - Andover 1962 (Box 1353, Folder 4)
      - [correspondence] (Box 1353, Folder 5)
      - Agenda 3rd Dartmouth Conf. - Andover (Box 1353, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence w/ Russians (Box 1353, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence re Andover Conference (Box 1353, Folder 8)
      - Philips Academy correspondence (Box 1353, Folder 9)
      - Soviet press release on conference (Box 1353, Folder 10)
      - Mary Harvey letter re rapporteur's notes (Box 1353, Folder 11)
      - P. Mosley report to Shepard Stone re Andover Conference (Box 1353, Folder 12)
      - Response to NC's editorial "Experiment at Andover" (Box 1353, Folder 13)
      - Interpretation III (Box 1353, Folder 14)
      - NC personal notes (Box 1353, Folder 15)
      - Information summary re nuclear testing (Box 1353, Folder 16)
      - [papers delivered, rapporteur's notes] (Box 1353, Folder 17)
      - III - 1962 Dartmouth Conference reprints (Box 1353, Folder 18)
      - Press clips & background information (Box 1353, Folder 19)
      - Grenville Clark statement made at Andover (Box 1353, Folder 20)
      - Publicity (Box 1353, Folder 21)
    - Dartmouth Conference 4
      - 1964 (Box 1354, Folder 1)
      - Russian visitors Nov. 1964 (Box 1354, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence with the Russians (Box 1354, Folder 3)
      - USSR Conf. (Box 1354, Folder 4)
      - Fourth Dartmouth Conference: 1964 Leningrad participants (Box 1354, Folder 5)
      - Fourth Conference: agenda Leningrad (Box 1354, Folder 6)
      - Joint communique of fourth Dartmouth Conference - Leningrad (Box 1354, Folder 7)
      - Memorandum to American participants on 4th conference (Box 1354, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence re invitations American participants (Box 1354, Folder 9)
      - NC summary report of conferences I-III prepared for Johnson Foundation (Box 1354, Folder 10)
      - Press release on fourth Dartmouth Conference (Box 1354, Folder 11)
      - Please identify [photos from Dartmouth Conference] (Box 1354, Folder 12)
      - Paul D. White's notes & report on fourth conference (Box 1354, Folder 13)
      - Marshall Shulman's report on 4th conference (notes) (Box 1354, Folder 14)
      - David Rockefeller's notes & report on 4th Dartmouth Conference (Box 1354, Folder 15)
      - Supplement to NC report on conference (Box 1354, Folder 16)
      - Rapporteur's notes: fourth Dartmouth Conf.: Leningrad (Box 1354, Folder 17)
      - Original Rapporteur's notes as edited by MKH (Box 1354, Folder 18)
      - Mary K. Harvey Correspondence (Box 1355, Folder 1)
      - Fourth Conference press clips (Box 1355, Folder 2)
      - NC's miscellaneous conference notes (Box 1355, Folder 3)
      - Possible editorial on Leningrad material (Box 1355, Folder 4)
      - Dartmouth Conf IV - Mrs. Renko's reading in Russian of NC's opening speech (Box 1355, Folder 5)
      - Financial & budget (Box 1355, Folder 6)
      - NC background material (Box 1355, Folder 7)
      - Travel & itineraries (Box 1355, Folder 8)
      - General information re Russian travel & tourism (Box 1355, Folder 9)
      - Notes on MLF (Box 1355, Folder 10)
      - Ad hoc committee members 1963 (Box 1355, Folder 11)
      - Ad hoc meeting, Washington, D.C. Aug. 2, 1963 (Box 1355, Folder 12)
      - Post Dartmouth Conference correspondence (Box 1355, Folder 13)
      - Nuclear test ban material (Box 1355, Folder 14)
      - Siscoe correspondence - State Dept. (Box 1356, Folder 1)
      - Post Leningrad Conference Correspondence 1964 (Box 1356, Folder 2)
      - 4th Dartmouth - 1964 Soviet material (Box 1356, Folder 3)
    - Dartmouth Conference 5
      - Related activities to Dartmouth Conferences 1969 (Box 1356, Folder 4)
      - Fifth Dartmouth Conference 1969 (Box 1356, Folder 5)
      - Schedule & agenda material - 5th Dartmouth Conference (Box 1356, Folder 6)
      - Invitation lists & correspondence with American participants re Sept. (Box 1356, Folder 7)
      - Invitations & correspondence (wires) (responses) re January conference (Box 1356, Folder 8)
      - NC personal folder at conference (Box 1356, Folder 9)
      - List of Soviet-American participants - 5th Dartmouth Conference (Box 1356, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence with the Russians (Box 1356, Folder 11)
      - Invitations re NC Party (Conn.) for conference participants (Box 1356, Folder 12)
      - News clips and miscellaneous (Box 1356, Folder 13)
      - Photographs re fifth Dartmouth Conf. (Box 1356, Folder 14)
      - Communique of fifth Dartmouth Conference (Box 1356, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence 1965-1968 re proposals for a fifth Dartmouth conference (Box 1356, Folder 16)
      - Rapporteur's notes - fifth Dartmouth Conference (Box 1357, Folder 1)
      - NC editorials on Dartmouth Confs. (Box 1357, Folder 2)
      - Pictures USSR (Box 1357, Folder 3)
      - Russian names and addresses (Box 1357, Folder 4)
      - Rapporteur's notes: fifth Dartmouth Conference, Rye, NY, January 13-19, 1969 (Box 1357, Folder 5)
    - Dartmouth Conference 7
      - [Dartmouth Conf. VII materials], 1972 (Box 1358, Box 1359)
    - Dartmouth Conference 8
      - [Dartmouth Conference VIII materials], 1974 (Box 1360, Box 1361)
    - Dartmouth Conference 9-17
      - [Dartmouth Conference IX materials], 1975 (Box 1362)
      - [Dartmouth Conference X materials], 1976 (Box 1363, Box 1364, Box 1365)
        includes corresp. re Russians 1963-1966
      - [Dartmouth Conference XI materials], 1977 (Box 1366, Box 1367)
      - [Dartmouth Conference XII materials], 1979 (Box 1367)
      - [Dartmouth Conference XIII materials], 1981 (Box 1368)
      - [Dartmouth Conference XIV materials], 1984 (Box 1368, Box 1369)
      - [Dartmouth Conference XV materials], 1986 (Box 1369)
      - [Dartmouth Conference XVI materials], 1988 (Box 1370, Box 1371)
      - [Dartmouth Conference XVII materials], 1990 (Box 1372)
    - U.S.-Chinese Writers Conference
      - [U.S.-Chinese Writers Conference I materials], 1982 (Box 1373, Box 1374)
      - [U.S.-Chinese Writers Conference II materials], 1984 (Box 1374)
      - [U.S.-Chinese Writers Conference III materials], 1986 (Box 1374)
      - [U.S.-Chinese Writers Conference IV materials], 1988 (Box 1374)
    - US-USSR Writers Conference 1
      - Evaluations & planning for #III conference (Box 1375, Folder 1-2)
      - Gordon Feller's summary of Soviet Writers Conferences (faxed from Pepperdine, May '90) (Box 1375, Folder 3)
      - [G. Feller corresp.] (Box 1375, Folder 4)
      - Gordon Feller proposal (funding) Soviet American Writers Conf. 1988 (Box 1375, Folder 5)
      - Gordon Feller - Soviet American Writers Conference 1988 (Box 1375, Folder 6)
      - Gordon Feller (materials sent) Aug. '87 (Box 1375, Folder 7)
      - [Gordon Feller materials] (Box 1375, Folder 8)
      - [unidentified Soviet Writers Conf.] (Box 1375, Folder 9)
      - US-USSR Writers Conference (Box 1375, Folder 10-11)
      - [publications] (Box 1376, Folder 1)
      - Bernstein-Random House briefing (US-USSR Writers Conf.) (Box 1376, Folder 2)
      - USSR Writers Conference 1977-1978 lists (Box 1376, Folder 3)
      - [unidentified] (Box 1376, Folder 4)
      - Record of Proceedings (Box 1376, Folder 5)
      - 1st Soviet American Writers Conference (Box 1376, Folder 6)
      - USSR 1977 (MS notes) (Box 1376, Folder 7)
    - US-USSR Writers Conference 2
      - Writers Conf. (confirming ltrs.) (Box 1376, Folder 8)
      - US-USSR Writers Conf. II NYC 1978 (Box 1377, Folder 1)
      - 2nd Soviet American Writers Conf. NYC Apr 25-27 1978 (Box 1377, Folder 2)
      - Participants - Misc. info (Box 1377, Folder 3)
      - Writers Conf. Misc. Corresp. (Box 1377, Folder 4)
      - [papers] (Box 1377, Folder 5)
      - Kettering planning cables (Box 1377, Folder 6)
      - Declaration of conscience, Soviet American Writers, SALT II (Box 1377, Folder 7)
      - Tatiana Kutriavtscva (Box 1377, Folder 8)
      - MS notes US-USSR Writers Conf. (Box 1377, Folder 9)
      - US-USSR Writers Conf. - mtg. notes (Box 1377, Folder 10)
      - [Saturday Review folder] (Box 1378, Folder 1)
      - [Mtg. notebook] (Box 1378, Folder 2)
      - US/USSR Writers Conf. (Box 1378, Folder 3)
    - US-USSR Writers Conference 3-9
      - [US-USSR Writers Conferences III-IX materials] (Box 1378, Box 1379)
  - Correspondence
    - Annual 1988
      - Misc. 1987 Corresp., 1988 Activities, A-AI (Box 1159)
      - AI-AZ, BA-BD (Box 1160)
      - BE-BZ (Box 1161)
      - BE-BZ cont., CA-CH (Box 1162)
      - CI-CZ, D (Box 1163)
      - D cont., E (Box 1164)
      - F-GZ (Box 1165)
      - GI-GZ cont., H-HO (Box 1166)
      - Holiday Cards, HP-HZ, I (Box 1167)
      - J-KO (Box 1168)
      - KP-LE (Box 1169)
      - LF-LZ, MA-MD (Box 1170)
      - MA-MD cont. (Box 1171)
      - ME-MZ (Box 1172)
      - N-O (Box 1173)
      - P-RE (Box 1174)
      - RI-SD (Box 1175)
      - SH-SO (Box 1176)
      - SP-T (Box 1177)
      - U-WE (Box 1178)
      - WF-Z (Box 1179)
    - Annual 1989
      - Activities (Box 1180, Folder 1-6)
      - A-B (Box 1180, Folder 7-9)
      - C-D (Box 1181, Folder 1-2)
      - E-G (Box 1181, Folder 3-4)
      - H-J (Box 1181, Folder 5)
      - K-L (Box 1182, Folder 1-2)
      - M-N (Box 1182, Folder 3)
      - O-R (Box 1182, Folder 4)
      - S-T (Box 1183, Folder 1)
      - U-Z (Box 1183, Folder 2)
    - Annual 1990
      - Activities (Box 1183, Folder 3-6)
      - Unanswered correspondence (Box 1184, Folder 1-4)
      - Correspondence answered by J. Anderson and E. Cousins (Box 1184, Folder 5)
      - A-B (Box 1185, Folder 1-2)
      - C (Box 1185, Folder 3)
      - D (Box 1185, Folder 4)
      - E-G (Box 1186, Folder 1-2)
      - H-J (Box 1186, Folder 3)
      - K-L (Box 1186, Folder 4)
      - M-N (Box 1187, Folder 1)
      - O-R (Box 1187, Folder 2-3)
      - S (Box 1187, Folder 4-5, Box 1188)
        (f. 1 in box 1188)
      - T-V (Box 1188, Folder 2)
      - W-Z (Box 1188, Folder 3)
      - Grateful fans (Box 1188, Folder 4)
      - Woody Clark (Box 1189, Folder 1)
      - George Lundberg (Box 1189, Folder 2)
      - Ruth Rosenwald (Box 1189, Folder 3)
      - Yan Yin (Box 1189, Folder 4)
    - Friends
      - Andre & Bea Baruch (Box 1190, Folder 1)
      - Tony diGesa (Box 1190, Folder 2)
      - Mary and Grey Dimond (Grenville Clark) (Box 1190, Folder 3)
      - Omar Fareed (Box 1190, Folder 4)
      - Dev Freeman (Box 1190, Folder 5)
      - Sy Gomberg (Box 1190, Folder 6)
      - Fr. Gerry Grant (Box 1190, Folder 7)
      - Gabrielle Griswold (Box 1190, Folder 8)
      - Halls: Bernice & David; Peter; Suzannah; Zaza & Cuy Hunt (Box 1190, Folder 9-13)
      - Joel Hammil (Box 1191, Folder 1)
      - Virginia/SMT Heenan (Box 1191, Folder 2-4)
      - Bill Hitzig (Box 1191, Folder 5-9, Box 1192)
        (folders 1-6 in box 1192)
      - Dori Lewis (Box 1192, Folder 7-8)
      - Dana Little (Box 1192, Folder 9-10)
      - Stephanie May (Box 1192, Folder 14-16)
      - McLuhan Family (Box 1193, Folder 1)
      - John Minahan (Box 1193, Folder 2)
      - Bill Millard (Box 1193, Folder 3)
      - Jean Sanderson (Box 1193, Folder 4)
      - Sallie Lou Parker (Box 1193, Folder 5)
      - Susan Schiefelbein (Box 1193, Folder 6-7)
      - Emily Scott (Box 1193, Folder 8)
      - E. Silvers (Box 1193, Folder 9)
      - Dorothy/Dottie Stout & Family (Box 1193, Folder 10-11)
      - Emily Suesskind (Box 1193, Folder 12)
      - Horace Sutton (Box 1193, Folder 13)
      - Fran Thompson (Box 1194, Folder 1-4)
      - Monte Thornton (Box 1194, Folder 5)
      - Richard and Sylvia Tobin (Box 1195, Folder 1)
      - Eleanor Wilson (Box 1195, Folder 2)
      - Neighbors (Box 1195, Folder 3)
      - Neighbors: Henry Noel (Box 1195, Folder 4)
      - WAWF/UWF friends (Box 1195, Folder 5)
      - Elizabeth Shenck (lecture agent) (Box 1195, Folder 6)
      - Cousins/Marshall Fund, Lenore Marshall (Box 1192, Folder 11-13)
      - Ravensbrueck Lapins (Box 1195, Folder 7)
      - Ravensbrueck Lapins: Caroline Farriday (Box 1195, Folder 8)
      - Misc. corresp. (Box 1195, Folder 9)
      - Special Invitations, telegrams, cards (Box 1195, Folder 10-13)
    - Important
      - A (Box 1196, Folder 1)
      - Adler (Box 1196, Folder 2)
      - Allen (Box 1196, Folder 3)
      - B (Box 1196, Folder 4)
      - Bowles, Chester (Box 1196, Folder 5-10)
      - Brown, John Mason (Box 1197, Folder 1)
      - Buckley, William (Box 1197, Folder 2)
      - Bundy, McGeorge (Box 1197, Folder 3)
      - Bundy, William (Box 1197, Folder 4)
      - Bush, George (Box 1197, Folder 5)
      - CA (Box 1197, Folder 6)
      - CH-CR (Box 1197, Folder 7)
      - Canfield, Cass (Box 1197, Folder 8)
      - Carter, Jimmy (Box 1197, Folder 9)
      - Casals, Pablo (Box 1197, Folder 10)
      - Cerf, Bennet (Box 1197, Folder 11)
      - Commager, Henry Steele (Box 1197, Folder 12)
      - Cranston, Allan (Box 1197, Folder 13)
      - D (Box 1197, Folder 14)
      - DeGolyer, Everette (Box 1198, Folder 1-5)
        (see also: Writings-Books-DeGolyer)
      - Deluise, Carol & Dom (Box 1198, Folder 6)
      - Dukakis (Box 1198, Folder 7)
      - E (Box 1198, Folder 8)
      - Eaton, Cyrus (Box 1198, Folder 9-10)
      - Eisenhower, D (Box 1199, Folder 1-2)
        no DE originals
      - F (Box 1199, Folder 3)
      - Ford, Gerald R. (Box 1199, Folder 4)
      - Farrell, James T. (Box 1199, Folder 5)
      - Fuller, R. Buckminster (Box 1199, Box 1200, Box 1201)
        (also f. 10 in box 1814)
      - Fromm, Erich (Box 1201, Folder 5)
      - G (Box 1201, Folder 6)
      - Gandhi, Indira (Box 1201, Folder 7)
      - Gandhi, M.K. - Gosh (Box 1201, Folder 8)
      - Golden, Harry (Box 1201, Folder 9)
      - Supreme Court Justices, appelate, district court justices (Box 1201, Folder 10)
      - Foreign government officials (Box 1201, Folder 11)
      - U.N. foreign officials (Box 1202, Folder 1)
      - Governors (Box 1202, Folder 2)
      - Mayors (Box 1202, Folder 3)
      - Meyner, Gov. Robt. - conf. 1960 (Box 1202, Folder 4)
      - State representatives (Box 1202, Folder 5)
      - U.S. representatives (Box 1202, Folder 6)
      - U.S. senators - Clark, Sen. Joseph S. (D. Pa.) (Box 1202, Folder 7-8)
      - U.S. senators - Kennedy, Edward (Box 1202, Folder 9)
      - U.S. senators - Simon, Sen. Paul (Box 1203, Folder 1)
      - U.S. senators - Cranston, Sen. Alan (Box 1203, Folder 2)
      - U.S. senators - A-G (Box 1203, Folder 3)
      - U.S. senators - H-L (Box 1203, Folder 4)
      - U.S. senators - M (Box 1203, Folder 5)
      - U.S. senators - N-Z (Box 1203, Folder 6)
      - White House staffs (Box 1203, Folder 7)
        (see also files of individual presidents)
      - Executive depts., agencies, Armed Services (Box 1204, Folder 1)
      - H (Box 1204, Folder 2-3)
      - Hammerstein, Oscar (Box 1204, Folder 4)
      - Herter, Christian (Box 1204, Folder 5)
      - Humphrey, Hubert (Box 1204, Folder 6-12, Box 1205)
        (folders 1-6 in box 1205)
      - I (Box 1205, Folder 7)
      - J (Box 1205, Folder 8)
      - Johnson, LBJ (Box 1205, Folder 9-13)
        no LBJ originals
      - K (Box 1206, Folder 1-2)
      - Kennedy, John F. & staff (Box 1206, Folder 3-15)
        no JFK originals
      - Kennedy, Edward (Box 1207, Folder 1)
      - Kennedy, Robert (Box 1207, Folder 2-7)
        no RFK originals
      - Kennedy, Mrs. JFK (Box 1207, Folder 8-10)
      - Kilpatrick, James J. (Box 1207, Folder 11)
      - King, Martin Luther (Box 1207, Folder 12)
        no MLK originals
      - LaRocque, Gene R. (Box 1207, Folder 14)
      - Lear, Norman (Box 1207, Folder 15)
      - Leinsdorf, Erich (Box 1207, Folder 16)
      - Luckman, Charles (Box 1208, Folder 7)
      - L (Box 1207, Folder 13)
      - Lindsay, John V. (Box 1208, Folder 1-4)
      - Linowitz, Sol (Box 1208, Folder 5)
      - Luce, Henry & Clare (Box 1208, Folder 6)
      - M (Box 1208, Folder 8-9)
      - Mathews, David (Box 1208, Folder 10)
      - Murphy, Franklin D. (Box 1209, Folder 1)
      - MacLeish, Archibald (Box 1209, Folder 2)
      - Mehta, Med (Box 1209, Folder 3)
      - Menninger, Karl (Box 1209, Folder 4)
      - Menninger, Ann Catherine (Box 1209, Folder 5)
      - Menninger, Roy & Barbara (Box 1209, Folder 6)
      - Menuhin, Yehudi (Box 1209, Folder 7)
      - Michener, James (Box 1209, Folder 8)
      - Muller, Robert (Box 1209, Folder 9-10)
      - Mumford, Lewis (Box 1209, Folder 11)
      - Muskie, Edmund (Box 1210, Folder 1-12)
      - N (Box 1210, Folder 13)
      - Nixon, Richard M. (Box 1210, Folder 14)
      - O (Box 1211, Folder 1)
      - Overstreet, Bonaro & Harry (Box 1211, Folder 2-3)
      - P (Box 1211, Folder 4)
      - Pauling, Linus (Box 1211, Folder 5)
      - R (Box 1211, Folder 6-7)
      - Reagan, Ronald & staff (Box 1211, Folder 8-9)
      - Rockefellers (Box 1211, Folder 10-12)
      - Romulo, Carlos (Box 1212, Folder 1-7)
      - Sa-Se (Box 1213, Folder 1)
      - Sh-Su (Box 1213, Folder 2)
      - Schlesinger, Arthur jr. (Box 1213, Folder 3)
      - Shotwell, James T (Box 1213, Folder 4-5)
      - Smith, Lillian (Box 1213, Folder 6)
      - Sorenson, Theodore (Box 1213, Folder 7)
      - Stevens, George (Box 1213, Folder 8)
      - Stone, Irving (Box 1213, Folder 9)
      - Stevenson, Adlai (Box 1214, Folder 1-13)
      - Szent-Gyorgyi, Albert (Box 1214, Folder 14)
      - Szilard, Leo (Box 1214, Folder 15)
      - T (Box 1215, Folder 1)
      - Thomas, Norman (Box 1215, Folder 2)
      - Truman, Harry S. (Box 1215, Folder 3)
      - U (Box 1215, Folder 4)
      - U Thant (Box 1215, Folder 5-9)
      - V (Box 1215, Folder 10)
      - W (Box 1215, Folder 11)
      - Wadsworth, James (Box 1215, Folder 12)
      - Wharton, John (Box 1216, Folder 1-9)
      - White, Paul Dudley (Box 1216, Folder 10)
      - XYZ (Box 1216, Folder 11)
    - International-Important
      - Nuclear Test Ban Materials, Citizens Committee for a Nuclear Test Ban Rep. to JFK, copies of corresp. with Nehru & Krushchev (Box 1217, Folder 1-11, Box 1218)
        (folders 1-5 in box 1218)
      - NC visit to Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, Dec. 1961 (Box 1218, Folder 6)
      - NC notebooks '62, '63; 3 steno notebooks, 1 notepad (Box 1219, Folder 1)
        includes notes from Khrushchev and Pope visits
      - Khrushchev photos (Box 1219, Folder 2)
        photos are newspaper clippings
      - Khrushchev greeting to Pope/Kennedy 1962; Encyclical copies (Box 1219, Folder 3)
      - Test Ban Treaty, JFK NYC, 1963 (Box 1219, Folder 4-6)
        posters of JFK & Khrushchev moved to box 1225
      - NC/Khrushchev Corresp, 1961-1963 (Box 1219, Folder 7-8)
        corresp. with Dobrynin
      - Visit to Gagra, 4/12/63 (Box 1220, Folder 1-3)
      - Khrushchev tapes (Box 1220, Folder 4)
        about Khrushchev tapes
      - Moscow Conference - Communist/worker parties, 1960 (Box 1220, Folder 5)
      - NC unidentifed quotes: JFK, Khrushchev, China (Box 1220, Folder 6)
      - Pope John XXIII Encyclical Letter, corresp. re, 1963 (Box 1220, Folder 7-10)
      - Msgr. Ignacio Cardinale Archbishop Dell Aqua (Box 1220, Folder 11, Box 1221)
        (folder 1 in box 1221)
      - Vatican corresp (Box 1221, Folder 2-5)
      - NC/JFK corresp. re visit to Pope John 1962, memos (Box 1221, Folder 6)
      - NC negotiations re Vietnam, research & xeroxes (mtg. with U Thant) (Box 1221, Folder 7-11)